(WHOOSHING)
- What is it?
- Some kind of signal, drawing us off course.
- Where are we?
- Earth. Utah, North America.
About half a mile underground.
When are we?
2012.
God, that's so close. So I should be 26.
(FLICKS SWITCH)
(ROSE) Blimey! It's a great big museum.
(DOCTOR) An alien museum.
Someone's got a hobby.
They must have spent a fortune.
Chunks of meteorite. Moondust.
The mileometer from the Roswell spaceship.
(ROSE) That's a bit of Slitheen.
That's a Slitheen's arm. It's been stuffed!
Oh! Look at you.
What is it?
An old friend of mine - well, enemy.
The stuff of nightmares, reduced to an exhibit.
I'm getting old.
- Is that where the signal's coming from?
- No. It's dead. The signal's alive.
Something's reaching out, calling for help.
(ALARM)
If someone collects aliens, then you're Exhibit A.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(MAN) Attention, all personnel.
Bad Wolf 0ne descending.
(ALARM)
I wanna wish you a very happy birthday, sir.
- The president conveys his best wishes.
- He's ten points down.
- I want him replaced.
- I don't think that's very wise, sir.
You're fired.
Wipe his memory. Put him on the road.
Memphis. Minneapolis.
A place beginning with M. So, the next
president - Republican or Democrat?
- Democrat, sir.
- Why?
They're just so funny, sir?
- What is your name?
- Goddard, sir. Diana Goddard.
- I like you. So where's the English kid?
- (ENGLISH ACCENT) Sir!
- I bought ten more artefacts at auction.
- Let me see 'em.
There's something more urgent.
We arrested two intruders 53 floors down.
- We don't know how they got in.
- In-thru-da window.
- In-thru-da window! That's funny!
- (LAUGHTER)
Bring 'em in, and tell Simmons
I want to visit my little pet.
Simmons, you'd better give me good news.
Is it talking?
(HARSH, METALLIC CRY)
Not exactly talking, no.
- Then what's it doing?
- Screaming. Is that any good?
(STRANGLED CRY)
And this is the last.
- Paid $800,000 for it.
- What does it do?
See the tubes on the side? It must be
to channel something - maybe fuel.
- I wouldn't hold it like that.
- Shut it.
- Really. That's wrong.
- Is it dangerous?
- No. It just looks silly.
- (SAFETY CATCHES CLICK)
You just need to be...
(HUMMING)
..delicate.
It's a musical instrument!
- And it's a long way from home.
- Here, let me.
- I did say delicate.
- (DISCORDANT TRILL)
It reacts to the smallest fingerprint.
It needs precision.
(ETHEREAL HUM)
Very good. Quite the expert.
As are you.
- (CLATTERING)
- Who are you?
- The Doctor. Who are you?
- Like you don't know (!)
This is the most valuable collection
of extraterrestrial artefacts in the world,
and you just stumbled in by mistake (!)
- Pretty much sums me up, yeah.
- How did you get in?
53 floors down.
With your little cat burglar accomplice.
- She's rather pretty.
- She's gonna smack you if you call her ''she''!
She's English! Hey, Little Lord Fauntleroy!
Got you a girlfriend.
- This is Mr Henry Van Statten.
- And who's he when he's at home?
- Mr Van Statten owns the internet.
- No one OWNS the internet.
- Let's keep the whole world thinking that way.
- So you're an expert in everything?
Anything you don't understand, you lock up.
- You claim greater knowledge?
- I don't need to.
And yet I captured you - right next to the Cage.
What were you doing down there?
- You tell me.
- The Cage contains my one living specimen.
- And what's that? Show me.
- You want to see it?
Blimey! You can smell the testosterone.
Goddard, inform the Cage we're heading down.
You, English, look after the girl. Go and canoodle
or spoon or whatever it is you do.
You, Doctor-With-No-Name,
come and see my pet.
We've tried everything.
The creature has shielded itself,
but there's definite signs of life inside.
Inside? Inside what?
I've had to take the power down.
The Metaltron is resting.
- Metaltron?
- Thought of it myself.
Good, isn't it?
Although I'd prefer to know its real name.
Put these on. The last guy that touched it...
..burst into flames.
I won't touch it, then.
Go ahead, Doctor. Impress me.
Don't open that door until we get a result.
(DOOR SLAMS)
I'm sorry about this. Mr Van Statten
might think he's clever, but never mind him.
I've come to help. I'm the Doctor.
(HARSH, METALLIC VOICE) Doctor?
- Impossible!
- THE Doctor?!
(FRENZIED CRY) Exterminate!
- Exterminate!
- Let me out!
- It's going to kill him.
- It's talking!
- (DALEK) You are an enemy of the Daleks.
You must be destroyed!
It's not working!
(LAUGHS)
Fantastic!
Oh, fantastic!
Powerless. Look at you.
- The great space dustbin (!) How does it feel?
- (STRANGLED CRY) Keep back!
What for? What are you gonna do to me?
If you can't kill,
then what are you good for, Dalek?
What's the point of you?
You're nothing!
What the hell are you here for?
(DALEK) I am waiting for orders.
- What does that mean?
- I am a soldier.
I was bred to receive orders.
- Well, you're never gonna get any. Not ever.
- I demand orders!
They're never gonna come. Your race is dead.
You all burnt. Ten million ships on fire.
The entire Dalek race, wiped out in one second.
You lie!
- I watched it happen. I MADE it happen!
- You destroyed us?
I had no choice.
(DALEK) And what of the Time Lords?
Dead.
They burnt with you.
The end of the last great Time War.
Everyone lost.
(DALEK) And the coward survived.
Oh, and I caught your little signal.
''Help me!'' Poor little thing (!)
But there's no one else coming
'cause there's no one else left.
(DALEK) I am alone in the universe.
Yep!
So are you.
We are the same.
We're not the same! I'm not...
No, wait.
Maybe we are.
You're right. Yeah, OK. You've got a point.
'Cause I know what to do.
I know what should happen.
I know what you deserve.
Exterminate!
(STRANGLED CRY)
- Have pity!
- Why should I? You never did!
Get him out!
Help me!
(VAN STATTEN) I saved your life.
Now talk to me.
- Talk to me!
- (DOCTOR) You've got to destroy it!
The last in the universe.
And now I know your name.
Dalek.
Speak to me, Dalek!
I am Henry Van Statten. Now recognise me!
Make it talk again, Simmons.
Whatever it takes.
(ADAM) Sorry about the mess.
Mr Van Statten lets me do my own thing
so long as I deliver the goods.
What do you think that is?
- A lump of metal?
- Yeah...
I think - well, I'm almost certain -
it's from the hull of a spacecraft.
The thing is, it's all true. Everything
the United Nations tries to keep quiet -
spacecraft, aliens, visitors to Earth.
- They really exist.
- That's amazing.
It sounds incredible, but I believe
the whole universe is teeming with life.
I'm gobsmacked, yeah.
- And you do what? Sit here and catalogue it?
- Best job in the world!
Imagine if you could get out there -
travel amongst the stars and see it for real.
I'd give anything. I don't think
it'll happen - not in our lifetime.
You never know. What about all those people
who say they've been inside spaceships
and talked to aliens?
I think they're nutters.
- Yeah. Me too!
- (THEY LAUGH)
- How did you end up here?
- Geniuses from all over the world come here.
Oh, right. You're a genius.
Sorry, but yeah. I can't help it.
I was born clever.
When I was eight,
I logged on to the US defence system.
- Nearly caused World War Three.
- Is that funny?
You should have seen them running about.
Fantastic!
- You sound like the Doctor.
- Are you and him...?
- No, we're just friends.
- Good.
Why is that good?
Just is.
So... Wouldn't you rather be downstairs?
You've got these bits of metal, but
Mr Van Statten's got a living creature down there.
Yeah. I did ask, but he keeps it to himself.
Although, if you're a genius, it doesn't take long
to patch through on the comms system.
Let's have a look, then.
(TAPPING KEYS)
It doesn't do much - the alien.
It's weird. It's kind of useless.
It's just like this great big pepperpot.
(DRILLING)
- (SCREAMING)
- It's being tortured. Where's the Doctor?
- I don't know.
- Take me down there now.
(DOCTOR) The metal is armour.
The creature's inside. It's a mutation.
The Dalek race was genetically engineered.
Every emotion was removed except hate.
Genetically engineered by whom?
By a genius, a man who was king
of his own world. You'd like him.
It's been on Earth for over 50 years,
sold from one collection to another.
- Why is it a threat now?
- Because I'm here. How did it reach Earth?
Records say it came from the sky
like a meteorite. It hit the Ascension Islands.
It burnt in its crater for three days.
In all that time, it was screaming.
It must have gone insane.
- It fell through time. The only survivor.
- You mentioned a war.
The Time War. The battle
between my people and the Dalek race.
- But you survived, too.
- Not by choice.
This means the Dalek isn't the only alien
on Earth, Doctor. There's you.
The only one of your kind in existence.
Now smile!
(BUZZING)
Two hearts. A binary vascular system.
Oh, I am so gonna patent this!
You don't just collect this stuff.
You scavenge it.
This technology has been falling to Earth
for centuries.
All it took was the right mind to use it properly.
Oh, the advances I've made from alien junk!
You have no idea, Doctor.
Broadband? Roswell.
Last year, my scientists cultivated bacteria from
the Russian crater. Do you know what we found?
The cure for the common cold.
Kept it within the laboratory, of course.
No need to get people excited. Why sell
one cure when I can sell 1,000 palliatives?
Do you know what a Dalek is, Van Statten?
A Dalek is honest. It does what it was born to do
for the survival of its species.
That creature is better than you.
In that case, I will be true to myself
and continue.
That thing downstairs
is going to kill every last one of us!
Nothing can escape the Cage.
(BUZZING)
It's woken up. It knows I'm here.
It's going to get out.
Van Statten, I swear, no one on this base
is safe. No one on this planet.
Agh!
- Hold it!
- Level three access.
Special clearance from Mr Van Statten.
Don't get too close.
Hello.
Are you in pain? I'm Rose Tyler.
My friend can help. He's called the Doctor.
What's your name?
(DALEK) Yes.
What?
I am in pain.
They torture me,
but still they fear me.
Do you fear me?
No.
I am dying.
No, we can help.
I welcome death.
But I am glad...
..that before I die
I have met a human
who was not afraid.
Isn't there anything I can do?
My race is dead.
I shall die alone.
- Rose, no!
- (SHE GASPS)
(DALEK) Genetic material extrapolated!
Initiate cellular reconstruction!
What the hell have you done?
What you gonna do? Sucker me to death (?)
(SCREAMS)
- Do something!
- Condition Red.
Condition Red. This is not a drill!
Release me if you want to live.
- You've got to keep it in that cell.
- It's all my fault.
It can't get out.
That lock's got a billion combinations.
A Dalek can calculate
1,000 billion combinations in a second.
(MAN) Open fire!
- Don't shoot it. I want it unharmed.
- Rose, get out of there!
De Maggio, get the civilians out alive.
- That is your job. You got that?
- Come with me.
Abandoning the Cage, sir.
We're losing power. It's draining the base.
It's draining the entire power supplies of Utah.
- It's downloading.
- Downloading what?
- The entire West Coast has gone down.
- It's not just energy.
That Dalek absorbed the internet.
It knows everything.
(DALEK) The Daleks survive in me!
- The cameras in the Vault are down.
- We've only got emergency power. Kill it now!
All guards to converge
on the Metaltron Cage immediately.
Civilians. Let 'em through.
Cover the north wall.
Maintain suppressing fire along the perimeter.
(AGONISED SCREAM)
Agh!
- Stop the shooting.
- But it's killing them.
They're dispensable. That Dalek is unique.
I don't want a scratch on it. Do you hear me?
Do you hear me?
(SHOOTING STOPS)
That's us, below the surface.
That's the Cage. That's the Dalek.
- Do you have any alien weapons?
- Yes, but the Dalek's between us and them.
We've got to keep that thing alive.
- We could seal the Vault.
- Trapping everyone.
Rose is down there. I won't let that happen.
- What's this area?
- Weapons testing.
Give guns to the technicians, the lawyers,
everyone. It's your only chance of killing it.
Stairs! That's more like it.
It hasn't got legs. It's stuck.
It's coming! Get up!
(ADAM) Great big alien death machine -
defeated by a flight of stairs.
(DE MAGGIO ) Listen to me.
I demand that you return to your Cage.
If you want to negotiate,
Mr Van Statten will agree to talk.
I accept that we imprisoned you
and maybe that was wrong, but people have died.
That stops right now.
The killing stops. Have you got that?
I demand that you surrender. Is that clear?
(DALEK) Elevate!
My God!
Adam, get her out of here.
- Come with us. You can't stop it.
- Someone's gotta try. Now get out!
Don't look back. Just run.
(SIZZLING BLAST AND SCREAM)
I thought you were the great expert.
Why not just reason with this Dalek?
It must be willing to negotiate.
- Everything needs something.
- What's the nearest town?
- Salt Lake City. Population one million.
- All dead.
- The Dalek will murder every living creature.
- Why?
Because it believes they should die.
Anything different is wrong.
It's the ultimate in racial cleansing,
and you've let it loose.
The Dalek is surrounded by a force field,
but it's not indestructible.
Concentrate your fire and you might get through.
Aim for the eyepiece. That's the weak spot.
Thank you, Doctor, but I think I know
how to fight one single tin robot (!)
Positions!
(COMMANDER) Hold your fire.
You two, get the hell out of there!
- It was looking at me.
- It wants to slaughter us.
- It was looking right at me.
- It's just a metal eye thing.
- It's looking all around.
- I don't know.
It's like there's something inside,
looking at me like...
Like it knows me.
On my mark...
Open fire!
(GODDARD ) We've got vision.
It wants us to see.
(MEN SCREAM IN AGONY)
Fall back!
Maybe we should consider
abandoning this place.
There's no power to the helipad.
- We can't get out.
- You said we could seal the Vault.
It was designed to be a bunker in a nuclear war.
Steel bulkheads close off the area.
- There's not enough power.
- Reroute the emergency power.
- We'd need a computer genius.
- Good thing you've got me, then!
- You want to help?
- I don't want to die, Doctor.
- Nobody knows this software better than me.
- Sir...
(DALEK) I shall speak only to the Doctor.
You're gonna get rusty.
(DALEK) I fed off the DNA of Rose Tyler.
Extrapolating the biomass
of a time traveller regenerated me.
- What's your next trick?
- I have been searching for the Daleks.
Yeah, I saw - downloading the internet.
What did you find?
- I scanned your satellites and radio telescopes.
- And?
(DALEK) Nothing.
(FRENZIED CRY)
Where shall I get my orders now?
- You're just a soldier without commands.
- Then I shall follow the Primary Order -
the Dalek instinct to destroy, to conquer!
What for? What's the point?
Don't you see it's all gone?
Everything you were, everything you stood for.
(DALEK) Then what should I do?
All right, then.
If you want orders, follow this one.
- Kill yourself.
- The Daleks must survive!
The Daleks have failed.
Why don't you make the Daleks extinct,
rid the universe of your filth?
Why don't you just die?
You would make a good Dalek.
Seal the Vault.
I'll feed power from the ground defences
to the bulkheads.
- It's years since I've worked so fast!
- Having fun?
She's still down there.
- (PHONE RINGS)
- (ROSE) This isn't the best time.
- (D0CT0R) Where are you?
- Level 49.
Keep moving.
The Vault's being sealed off up at level 46.
- Can't you stop 'em closing?
- I can't wait and I can't help you.
(D0CT0R) Now, for God's sake, run!
- Done it. We've got power.
- The Dalek's behind them.
Nearly there. Give us two seconds.
I can't sustain the power. The system is failing.
We have to close the bulkheads.
I'm sorry.
(WHIRRING)
- Come on!
- (BEEPING AND WHIRRING)
The Vault is sealed.
Rose, where are you? Did you make it?
Sorry. I was a bit slow.
See you, then, Doctor.
It wasn't your fault.
Remember that, OK? It wasn't your fault.
And do you know what?
I wouldn't have missed it for the world.
- (DALEK) Exterminate!
- (SIZZLING BLAST)
- I killed her.
- I'm sorry.
I said I'd protect her. She was only here
because of me, and you're sorry?
I could have killed that Dalek in its cell,
but you stopped me.
- It was the prize of my collection.
- Was it worth it?
Worth all those men's deaths? Worth Rose?
Let me tell you something.
Mankind goes into space to explore.
- To be part of something greater.
- Exactly! I wanted to touch the stars.
You just want to drag the stars down,
underground underneath tons of sand and dirt,
and label them.
You're as far from the stars as you can get.
And you took her down with you.
She was 19 years old.
Go on, then. Kill me.
Why are you doing this?
I am armed. I will kill.
- It is my purpose.
- They're all dead because of you.
They are dead because of us.
And now what? What are you waiting for?
I feel your fear.
What do you expect?
Daleks do not fear. Must not fear.
You gave me life.
What else have you given me?
I am contaminated.
- You were quick on your feet (!)
- I'm not the one who sealed the Vault.
(DALEK) 0pen the bulkhead or Rose Tyler dies.
(GASPS) You're alive!
Can't get rid of me (!)
I thought you were dead.
(DALEK) 0pen the bulkhead!
(R0SE) Don't do it.
(DALEK) What use are emotions
if you will not save the woman you love?
I killed her once.
I can't do it again.
What do we do now, you bleeding heart?
What the hell do we do?
- Kill it.
- The alien weapons are in the Vault.
Only the catalogued ones.
Broken.
Hairdryer.
Mr Van Statten tends to wipe people's memory.
I kept this in case I needed
to fight my way out one day.
- What, YOU in a fight?
- I could do.
Are you gonna throw your A levels at 'em (?)
Oh, yes.
Lock and load!
- Don't kill 'em. You didn't kill me.
- But why not?
Why are you alive?
My function is to kill.
What am I?
Don't move. It's beginning to question itself.
(DALEK) Van Statten, you tortured me.
- Why?
- I wanted to help you.
I don't know. I thought if we could get through
to you, we could mend you. I wanted you better.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. I swear.
I just wanted you to talk!
(DALEK) Then hear me talk now. Exterminate!
(FRENZIED CRY) Exterminate! Exterminate!
Don't do it. Don't kill him!
You don't have to do this anymore.
There must be something else, not just killing.
What else is there? What do you want?
I want freedom.
You're out. You made it.
- I never thought I'd feel the sunlight again.
- How...does...it...feel?
(WHIRRING)
(DOCTOR) Get out of the way!
Get out of the way now!
- No. I won't let you do this.
- That thing killed hundreds of people.
It's not the one pointing the gun at me.
I've got to do this. I've got to end it.
The Daleks destroyed my home, my people.
- I've got nothing left.
- Look at it.
What's it doing?
It wants the sunlight.
- It can't...
- It couldn't kill Van Statten or me.
It's changing.
What about you, Doctor?
What the hell are you changing into?
I couldn't...
I wasn't...
Oh, Rose. They're all dead.
(DALEK) Why do we survive?
I don't know.
I am the last of the Daleks.
You're not even that.
Rose did more than regenerate you.
You've absorbed her DNA.
You're mutating.
Into what?
Something new.
I'm sorry.
Isn't that better?
Not for a Dalek.
(DALEK) I can feel.
So many ideas.
So much darkness.
Rose, give me orders.
Order me to die.
I can't do that.
(DALEK) This is not life.
This is sickness.
I shall not be like you.
Order my destruction!
Obey! Obey!
Obey!
Do it.
Are you frightened, Rose Tyler?
Yeah.
So am I.
Exterminate.
- What the hell are you doing?
- 200 personnel dead because of you, sir.
Wipe his memory
and leave him by the road someplace.
You can't do this. I am Henry Van Statten!
By tonight, you'll be a homeless, brainless junkie
living on the streets
of San Diego, Seattle, Sacramento.
Someplace beginning with S.
(DOCTOR) A piece of home. Better than nothing.
- Is that the end of it, the Time War?
- I'm the only one left.
I win. How about that (?)
The Dalek survived.
Maybe some of your people did, too.
I know. In here.
- Feels like there's no one.
- Well, then.
- Good thing I'm not going anywhere.
- Yeah.
We'd better get out. Van Statten's disappeared.
Goddard says they're filling this with cement.
- About time!
- I'll have to go back home.
You'd better hurry up.
- Next flight to Heathrow is at 1500.
- Adam said that he wanted to see the stars.
Tell him to stand outside, then.
He's all on his own, and he DID help.
- He left you there.
- So did you.
- We've got to leave!
- Plus, he's a bit pretty.
I hadn't noticed.
- On your own head.
- (ADAM) What are you doing?
She said cement! She wasn't joking.
We're going to get sealed in!
Doctor? What are you doing
standing inside a box?
(TARDIS ROARS INTO LIFE)
Rose?
(WHOOSHING)
The fourth great and bountiful human empire -
Planet Earth at its height.
Kronkburger - one cheese, one pajatos.
Something's wrong.
- My watch must be wrong.
- Your history's not as good as you thought.
- It's perfect.
- Obviously not.
I can taste it.
Engage safety.
(MAN) Someone shouldn't be here.
- Who are you?
- I'm the Editor.
What's happening?
(WOMAN) And spike.
Agh!