You are the Weakest Link.
This isn't just a game.
There's something else going on.
-We have contestants outside of the games.
-The games continue.
(DOCTOR) This Is Satellite Five.
1 0,000 channels. All beaming down from here.
My Masters, they fear the Doctor.
Tell me, who are they?
I saw you die!
-(JACK) That's Impossible. They were destroyed.
-Obviously they survived.
We have your associate.
You will obey or she will be exterminated.
-Rose?
-Yes, Doctor.
I'm coming to get you.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME MUSIC)
You know the Doctor. You understand him.
-You will predict his actions.
-I don't know!
-And even if I did, I wouldn't tell you.
-Predict! Predict! Predict!
Tardis detected In flight.
-Launch missiles! Exterminate!
-You can't!
The Tardis hasn't got any defences.
You're gonna kill him.
You have predicted correctly.
We've got incoming!
The extrapolator's working.
We've got a fully functional force-field.
-Try saying that when you're drunk.
-And for my next trick....
(WHOOSHING)
Rose, get down!
-Get down, Rose!
-Exterminate!
You did it.
-Feels like I haven't seen you in years.
-I told you I'd come and get you.
-Never doubted it.
-I did. You all right?
-Yeah. And you?
-Not bad. Been better.
-Don't I get a hug?
-Oh, come here.
I was talking to him. Welcome home.
-Oh! I thought I'd never see you again.
-You were lucky, that was just a one-shot wonder.
Drained the gun of all its power supply.
Now it's just a piece of junk.
Patience, my brethren.
(ROSE) You said they were extinct.
How come they're still alive?
One minute
they're the greatest threat in the universe,
the next minute
they vanished out of time and space.
They went off to fight a bigger war.
The Time War.
-I thought that was just a legend.
-I was there.
The war between the Daleks and the Time Lords,
with the whole of creation at stake.
My people were destroyed
but they took the Daleks with them.
I almost thought it was worth it.
And now it turns out they died for nothing.
There's thousands of them now.
We could hardly stop one.
What are we gonna do?
No good stood round here chinwagging.
Human race, you'd gossip all day.
The Daleks have got the answers.
Let's go and meet the neighbours.
You can't go out there!
-Exterminate!
Is that it? Useless. Nul points!
It's all right, come on out.
That force-field can hold back anything.
Almost anything.
-Yes, but I wasn't going to tell them that. Thanks.
-Sorry.
Do you know what they call me
in the ancient legends of the Dalek homeworld?
The Oncoming Storm.
You might have removed all your emotions,
but I reckon right down deep in your DNA,
there's one little spark left. And that's fear.
Doesn't it just burn when you face me?
So tell me, how did you survive the Time War?
They survived through me.
Rose. Captain.
This is the Emperor of the Daleks.
You destroyed us, Doctor.
The Dalek race died In your Inferno.
But my ship survived, falling through time,
crippled but alive.
-I get it....
-Do not Interrupt!
I think you're forgetting something.
I'm the Doctor
and if there's one thing I can do, it's talk.
I've got five billion languages
and you haven't got one way of stopping me.
So if anybody's gonna shut up, it's you!
Okie-doke. So, where were we?
We waited here, In the dark space,
damaged but rebuilding.
Centuries passed
and we quietly Infiltrated the systems of Earth,
harvesting the waste of humanity.
The prisoners, the refugees,
the dispossessed, they all came to us.
The bodies were filleted, pulped, sifted.
The seed of the human race Is perverted.
0nly one cell In a billion was fit to be nurtured.
So you created an army of Daleks out of the dead.
That makes them half human.
Those words are blasphemy!
-Do not blaspheme!
Do not blaspheme!
Everything human has been purged.
I cultivated
pure and blessed Dalek.
Since when did the Daleks
have a concept of blasphemy?
I reached Into the dirt and made new life.
I am the God of all Daleks!
-Worship him!
Worship him!
They're insane.
Hiding in silence for hundreds of years,
that's enough to drive anyone mad.
But it's worse than that.
Driven mad by your own flesh.
The stink of humanity.
You hate your own existence.
And that makes them more deadly than ever.
-We're going.
-You may not leave my presence!
-Stay where you are!
-Exterminate!
(ECHOING) Exterminate! Exterminate!
-Worship him!
You will be exterminated!
(WHOOSHING)
Turn everything up! All transmitters,
full power, wide open, now! Do it!
-What does this do?
-Stops the Daleks from transmitting on board.
How did you get on? Did you contact Earth?
I tried to warn them, but all they did was suspend
our licence 'cause we stopped the programmes.
And the planet's just sitting there. Defenceless.
Lynda, what are you still doing on board?
I told you to evacuate everyone!
-She wouldn't go.
-I didn't wanna leave you.
There weren't enough shuttles anyway
or I wouldn't be here.
We've got about 1 00 people
stranded on Floor Zero.
Listen, my name's Rodrick.
I won the game, where's my money?
Is anyone listening? Where's my money?
Oh, my God. The Fleet is moving.
They're on their way!
Purify the Earth with fire.
The planet will become my temple
and we shall rise.
This will be our paradise!
Dalek plan, big mistake,
'cause what've they left me with?
Anyone? Anyone? Come on, it's obvious!
A great big transmitter. This station!
If I can change the signal,
fold it back, sequence it? Anyone?
-You've got to be kidding.
-Give the man a medal!
-A Delta Wave?
-A Delta Wave!
-What's a Delta Wave?
-A wave of Van Cassadyne energy.
It fries your brain. Stand in the way
of a Delta Wave and your head gets barbecued.
And this place can transmit a massive wave.
Wipe out the Daleks!
Get started and do it, then!
Trouble is, wave this size, building this big,
brain as clever as mine,
should take about three days.
-How long till the Fleet arrive?
-22 minutes.
(JACK) We've now got a force-field,
so they can't blast us out of the sky.
But that doesn't stop
the Daleks from physically invading.
-Do they know about the Delta Wave?
-They'll have worked it out at the same time.
So, they want to stop the Doctor.
That means they've got to get to this level, 500.
Now, I can concentrate the extrapolator
on the top six levels, 500 to 495.
So they'll penetrate the station below that
at level 494 and fight their way up.
-Who are they fighting?
-Us.
What are we fighting with?
The guards had guns with bastic bullets,
that's enough to blow a Dalek wide open.
There's five of us.
Rose, you can help me.
I need all these wires stripping bare.
-Right, now there's four of us.
-Then let's move it!
Into the lift, isolate the lift controls.
I just wanna say...thanks, I suppose.
-And I'll do my best.
-Me, too.
It's been fun.
-But I guess this is goodbye.
-Don't talk like that.
The Doctor's gonna do it, you just watch him.
Rose.
You are worth fighting for.
Wish I'd never met you, Doctor.
I was much better off as a coward.
See you in hell.
He's gonna be all right, isn't he?
(PEOPLE ARGUING)
One last time! Any more volunteers?
There's an army about to invade this station.
I need every last citizen to mount a defence.
Don't listen to him! There aren't any Daleks.
They disappeared thousands of years ago.
Thanks. As for the rest of you,
the Daleks will enter the station at Floor 494,
and as far as I can tell,
they'll head up, not down.
But that's not a promise.
So here's a few words of advice.
Keep quiet.
And if you hear fighting up above,
if you hear us dying...
then tell me that the Daleks aren't real.
Don't make a sound.
Let's go.
Suppose....
-What?
-Nothing.
-You said suppose.
-No, I was just thinking.
I mean, obviously you can't,
but you've got a time machine.
Why can't you just go back to last week
and warn them?
Soon as the Tardis lands, in that second,
I become part of events. Stuck in the timeline.
Yeah, I thought it'd be something like that.
There's another thing the Tardis could do.
It could take us away. We could leave.
Let history take its course.
We go to Marbella in 1 989.
-Yeah, but you'd never do that.
-No, but you could ask.
-Never even occurred to you, did it?
-Well, I'm just too good.
(ELECTRONIC BUZZING)
The Delta Wave's started building.
How long does it need?
Is that bad?
Okay, it's bad. How bad is it?
Rose Tyler, you're a genius! We can do it!
If I use the Tardis to cross
my own timeline.... Yes!
Hold that down and keep position.
-What's it do?
-Cancels the buffers.
If I'm very clever, and I'm more than clever,
I'm brilliant,
I might just save the world. Or rip it apart.
-I'd go for the first one.
-Me, too.
Now, I've just got to go and power up
the Game Station. Hold on!
Doctor, what are you doing?
Can I take my hand off? It's moving.
Doctor, let me out!
Let me out!
Doctor, what have you done?
This Is Emergency Programme 0ne.
Rose, now listen, this Is Important.
If this message Is activated
then It can only mean one thing.
We must be In danger. And I mean fatal.
I'm dead or about to die any second
with no chance of escape.
-No!
-And that's okay. Hope It's a good death.
But I promised to look after you
and that's what I'm doing.
-The Tardis Is taking you home.
-I won't let you!
And I bet you're fussing and moaning now.
Typical! But hold on and just listen a bit more.
The Tardis can never return for me.
Emergency Programme 0ne means
I'm facing an enemy that
should never get their hands on this machine.
So this Is what you should do,
let the Tardis die.
Just let this old box gather dust.
No one can open It, no one will even notice It.
Let it become a strange little thing
standing on a street corner.
And over the years the world will move on
and the box will be buried.
And If you want to remember me,
then you can do one thing. That's all. 0ne thing.
Have a good life.
Do that for me, Rose. Have a fantastic life.
You can't do this to me. You can't.
Take me back! Take me back!
No!
Come on, fly. How do you fly?
Come on, help me!
I knew it!
I was all the way down Clifton Parade
and I heard the engines.
I thought, ''There's only one thing
that makes a noise like that.''
What is it?
Rose, I've called up the internal laser codes.
There should be a different number on
every screen. Can you read them out to me?
-She's not here.
-Of all the times to take a leak!
When she gets back, tell her to read me the codes.
-She's not coming back.
-What do you mean? Where did she go?
-Just get on with your work.
-You took her home, didn't you?
Yeah.
The Delta Wave. Is it ever gonna be ready?
(DALEK EMPEROR) Tell him the truth, Doctor.
There Is every possibility the Delta Wave
could be complete but no possibility of refining It.
The Delta Wave must kill
every living thing In Its path,
with no distinction between human and Dalek.
All things will die. By your hand.
Doctor, the range of this transmitter
covers the entire Earth.
(DALEK EMPEROR) You would destroy Daleks
and humans together.
If I am God,
the creator of all things,
then what does that make you, Doctor?
There are colonies out there.
The human race would survive in some shape
or form. But you're the only Daleks in existence.
The whole universe is in danger if I let you live.
Do you see, Jack?
That's the decision I've got to make
for every living thing.
Die as a human or live as a Dalek.
-What would you do?
-You sent her home. She's safe.
-Keep working.
-But he will exterminate you!
Never doubted him, never will.
Now, you tell me, God of all Daleks,
'cause there's one thing I never worked out.
The words, ''Bad Wolf'',
spread across time and space,
everywhere, drawing me in.
-How did you manage that?
-I did nothing.
Come on, there's no secrets now, Your Worship.
They are not part of my design.
This Is the truth of God.
(JACKIE) And it's gone upmarket, this place.
They're doing little tubs of coleslaw now.
It's not very nice. It tastes a bit sort of clinical.
Have you tried that new pizza place
on Minto Road?
-What's it selling?
-Pizza.
-That's nice. Do they deliver?
-Yeah.
Oh, Rose, have something to eat.
200,000 years in the future he's dying
and there's nothing I can do.
Like you said, 200,000 years, it's way off.
But it's not, it's now.
That fight is happening right now.
And he's fighting for us!
For the whole planet!
And I'm just sitting here eating chips!
Listen to me. God knows I've hated that man,
but right now I love him and do you know why?
'Cause he did the right thing.
He sent you back to me.
What do I do every day, Mum? What do I do?
Get up, catch the bus,
go to work, come back home,
-eat chips and go to bed, is that it?
-That's what the rest of us do.
-I can't.
-Why, 'cause you're better than us?
No, I didn't mean that!
But it was....
It was a better life.
I don't mean all the travelling and...
seeing aliens and spaceships
and things, that don't matter.
The Doctor showed me
a better way of living your life.
You know he showed you, too.
That you don't just give up.
You don't just let things happen.
You make a stand. You say no.
You have the guts to do what's right
when everyone else just runs away!
And I just can't....
Right, Lynda, you are my eyes and ears.
When the Daleks get in, you can follow them
on that screen and report it to me.
-Understood.
-They'll detect you.
The door is made of hydra combination,
it should keep them out.
-Should?
-It's the best I can do.
How long till the Fleet arrives?
(PROGRAMMER) They accelerated.
This is it! Ladies and gentlemen, we are at war.
You can't spend the rest of your life
thinking about the Doctor.
-But how do I forget him?
-You've got to start living your own life.
A proper life. Like the kind he's never had.
The sort of life that you could have with me.
Over here, it's over here as well!
That's been there for years.
It's just a phrase, it's just words!
I thought it was a warning.
Maybe it's the opposite.
Maybe it's a message.
The same words written down now
and 200,000 years in the future.
It's a link between me and the Doctor.
Bad Wolf here, Bad Wolf there.
Yeah, but if it's a message, what's it saying?
It's telling me I can get back.
The least I can do is help him escape!
Stand your ground, everyone.
Follow my commands. And good luck.
You were right.
They're forcing the air lock on 494.
All the Tardis needs to do is
make a return trip. Just reverse.
Yeah, but we still can't do it.
The Doctor always said the Tardis was telepathic.
This thing is alive, it can listen.
-It's not listening now, is it?
-We need to get inside it.
Last time I saw you, with the Slitheen,
this middle bit opened.
And there was this light
and the Doctor said It was the heart of the Tardis.
If we can open it, I can make contact.
I can tell it what to do.
-Rose, if you go back, you're gonna die.
-That's a risk I've got to take.
'Cause there's nothing left for me here.
-Nothing?
-No.
Okay, if that's what you think,
let's get this thing open.
(JACK) 0kay, activate Internal lasers.
Slice them up.
Defences have gone offline.
The Daleks have overridden the lot.
You lied to me! The bullets don't work!
Faster!
Come on!
It's not moving!
Advance guard have made it to 495.
-Jack, how are we doing?
-495 should be good. I like 495.
Identify yourself!
You are the Weakest Link. Goodbye!
Yes!
You are the Weakest Link.. ..
(WARPED VOICE) Goodbye.
Proceed to next level.
They're flying up the ventilation shafts.
No, wait a minute.
Oh, my God. Why are they doing that?
They're going down.
Exterminate! Exterminate.. ..
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Exterminate! Exterminate!
You can't! You don't exist!
It's not fair! I won the game! I should be rich!
-I'm a winner! You can't do this to me!
-Exterminate!
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
Floor Zero. They killed them all.
It was never gonna work, sweetheart.
And the Doctor knew that.
He just wanted you to be safe.
-I can't give up.
-Lock the door. Walk away.
-Dad wouldn't give up.
-He's not here, is he?
-And even if he was, he'd say the same.
-No, he wouldn't.
He'd tell me to try anything.
If I could save the Doctor's life, try anything.
-We're never gonna know.
-Well, I know. 'Cause I met him.
-I met Dad.
-Don't be ridiculous.
-The Doctor took me back in time and I met Dad.
-Don't say that.
You remember when Dad died,
there was someone with him?
A girl, a blonde girl. She held his hand.
You saw her from a distance, Mum, you saw her.
Think about it. That was me. You saw me.
-Stop it!
-That's how good the Doctor....
Stop it! Just stop it!
-Lynda, what's happening on Earth?
-The Fleet's descending.
They're bombing whole continents.
Europa, Pacifica, the New American Alliance.
Australasia's just, er...gone.
This Is perfection.
I have created heaven on Earth.
Floor 499, we're the last defence.
The bullets should work
if you concentrate them on the Daleks' eyestalk.
I've got the force-field at maximum,
so Dalek firepower should be at its weakest.
I'm only here 'cause of you.
I joined the Programme 'cause you were on it.
Am I supposed to say, ''When this is all over,
''if we're still alive,
maybe we could go for a drink?''
-That'd be nice.
-Yeah, well, tough.
There's gotta be something else we can do.
Mum was right. Maybe we should
just lock the door and walk away.
I'm not having that.
I'm not having you just give up now, no way.
We just need something stronger than my car.
Something bigger, something like that.
Right, you've only got this until 6:00,
so get on with it.
-Mum, where the hell did you get that from?
-Rodrigo. He owes me a favour.
Never mind why.
But you were right about your dad, sweetheart.
He was full of mad ideas
and it's exactly what he would have done.
Now, get on with it before I change my mind.
Open fire!
It's not working!
Concentrate your fire. Eyestalk 2:00!
Eye vision Is impaired! I cannot see!
We did it!
No. No!
I've got a problem.
(DALEK) Human female detected.
-They've found me.
-You'll be all right, Lynda.
That side of the station's
reinforced against meteors.
Hope so.
You know what they say about Earth workmanship.
Last man standing!
For God's sake, Doctor,
finish that thing and kill them!
Finish that thing and kill mankind.
-Keep going!
-Put your foot down!
-Faster!
-Give it some more, Mickey!
Keep going!
Come on! Come on!
-Keep going!
-Give it some more!
Rose!
(WHOOSHING)
Doctor! You've got 20 seconds maximum.
-Exterminate!
-I kind of figured that.
It's ready!
You really wanna think about this.
'Cause if I activate the signal,
every living creature dies.
I am Immortal.
-Do you wanna put that to the test?
-I want to see you become like me.
Hail the Doctor, the Great Exterminator.
-I'll do it!
-Then prove yourself, Doctor!
What are you? Coward or killer?
Coward.
Any day.
Mankind will be harvested
because of your weakness.
And what about me?
Am I becoming one of your angels?
You are the heathen.
You will be exterminated.
Maybe it's time.
(WHOOSHING)
Alert! Tardis materialising!
You will not escape!
-What have you done?
-I looked into the Tardis.
-And the Tardis looked into me.
-You looked into the time vortex.
Rose, no one's meant to see that.
This Is the Abomination!
Exterminate!
I am the Bad Wolf. I create myself.
I take the words...
I scatter them in time and space.
A message to lead myself here.
Rose, you've got to stop this!
You've got to stop this now!
You've got the entire vortex running
through your head. You're gonna burn!
I want you safe.
My Doctor.
Protected from the false god.
You cannot hurt me! I am Immortal!
You are tiny.
I can see the whole of time and space.
Every single atom of your existence
and I divide them.
Everything must come to dust.
All things. Everything dies.
-The Time War ends.
-I will not die!
I cannot die!
Rose, you've done it, now stop.
Just let go!
How can I let go of this?
I bring life.
But this is wrong!
-You can't control life and death!
-But I can.
The sun and the moon, the day and night.
But why do they hurt?
The power's gonna kill you. And it's my fault!
I can see everything.
All that is, all that was.
All that ever could be.
That's what I see. All the time.
-And doesn't it drive you mad?
-My head.
-Come here.
-It's killing me.
I think you need a doctor.
(WHOOSHING)
-What happened?
-Don't you remember?
It's like...
There was this singing.
That's right, I sang a song
and the Daleks ran away.
I was at home.
No, I wasn't. I was in the Tardis and...
there was this light.
I can't remember anything else.
Rose Tyler.
I was gonna take you to so many places.
Barcelona, not the city Barcelona,
the planet Barcelona, you'd love it.
Fantastic place. They've got dogs with no noses.
Imagine how many times a day you end up
telling that joke and it's still funny!
Then why can't we go?
Maybe you will, and maybe I will, but not like this.
You're not making sense.
I might never make sense again.
I might have two heads or no head!
Imagine me with no head.
And don't say that's an improvement!
But it's a bit dodgy this process.
You never know what you're gonna end up with.
-Doctor!
-Stay away!
Doctor, tell me what's going on.
I absorbed all the energy of the time vortex
and no one's meant to do that.
Every cell in my body is dying.
-Can't you do something?
-Yeah, I'm doing it now!
Time Lords have this little trick.
It's sort of a way of cheating death.
Except...
it means I'm gonna change...
and I'm not gonna see you again.
Not like this, not with this daft old face.
-And before I go....
-Don't say that!
Rose...
before I go I just wanna tell you,
you were fantastic.
Absolutely fantastic.
And do you know what?
So was I.
Hello, okay.
New teeth, that's weird. So, where was I?
Oh, that's right, Barcelona!