(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
(BEEPING)
- Bye!
- See you later.
(LAUGHS)
Bye!
(TANN0Y) The store will be closing
in five minutes. Thank you.
Hey!
Wilson?
Wilson, I've got the lottery money.
Wilson. Are you there?
I can't hang about
'cause they're closing the shop.
Wilson!
Oh, come on.
(CLATTERING)
Hello?
Hello, Wilson. It's Rose.
Wil...Wilson?
Wilson?
Wilson!
(DOOR SLAMS)
You're kidding me!
(CLATTERING AND BANGING)
Is that someone mucking about?
Who is it?
(CREAKING PLASTIC)
You got me. Very funny (!)
Right, I've got the joke. Whose idea was this?
Is it Derek's? Is it?
Derek, is this you?
(CREAKING PLASTIC)
Run!
- You pulled his arm off!
- Yep. Plastic.
Nice trick. Who were they?
- Is it a student thing?
- Why would they be students?
- I don't know.
- You said it. Why students?
That many people dressed up and being silly.
They gotta be students.
That makes sense. Well done.
- Thanks.
- They're not students.
Wilson will call the police.
- Wilson?
- Chief electrician.
Wilson's dead.
- That's not funny. That's sick.
- Mind your eyes.
I've had enough of this now. Who are you, then?
Who's that lot down there?
I said who are they?
They're living plastic creatures.
They're controlled by a relay device on the roof,
which would be a problem if I didn't have this.
I'm going to blow it up,
and I might well die in the process,
but don't worry about me -
go home and have your beans on toast.
If you tell anyone about this,
you'll get them killed.
- I'm the Doctor. You are?
- Rose.
Nice to meet you, Rose. Run for your life!
(BEEPING HORN)
(DRIVER) Watch it!
(EXPLOSION)
(MAN) Police investigate
a fire in Central London.
I know. It's on the telly. It's everywhere.
She's lucky to be alive!
It's aged her. Skin like an old Bible.
You'd think I was HER daughter. Here's himself.
I've been phoning your mobile. You could have
been dead. I can't believe the shop went up!
I'm fine. Don't make a fuss.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
- What caused it?
- I wasn't in the shop. I didn't see anything.
Debbie knows a man on the ''Mirror''.
500 quid for an interview.
Brilliant. Give it here.
You've got to find some way of making money.
I'm not bailing you out.
- (PHONE RINGS)
- Bev! She's alive!
I've told her. Sue for compensation.
She was within seconds of death!
- Is that tea? You need something stronger.
- I'm all right.
You deserve a proper drink.
- Let's go down the pub.
- Is there a match on?
- No! I'm just thinking about you.
- There's a match on.
- We could catch the last five minutes.
- Go on, then. I'm fine. Go. Get rid of that.
- Bye!
- Bye.
(CHOKES)
(MAN) It's thought there's very little chance
of saving the infrastructure.
(CREAKING PLASTIC)
(BEEPING)
(MUM) There's no point in getting up,
sweetheart. You've got no job to go to.
There's Finch's.
- They've always got jobs.
- Oh, great. The butcher's (!)
It might do you good. That shop gave you
airs and graces. I mean it about compensation.
You've had shock and trauma.
Arianna got 2,000 quid off the council 'cause
the old man at the desk said she looked Greek.
She IS Greek, but that's not the point.
It was a valid claim.
(CAT FLAP RATTLES)
Mum, I told you to nail that cat flap down.
We're gonna get strays.
- I did it weeks back!
- You thought about it.
What are you doing here?
- I live here.
- What for?
'Cause I do. I'm only here
'cause someone blew up my job.
I must have the wrong signal. You're not plastic,
are you? No, bonehead. Bye, then.
Inside. Right now.
(MUM) Who is it?
It's about last night. Give us ten minutes.
She deserves compensation.
Oh, we're talking millions!
Um...
- I'm in my dressing gown.
- Yes, you are.
There's a strange man in my bedroom.
Yes, there is.
Well, anything could happen.
No.
- Don't mind the mess. Do you want a coffee?
- Might as well, thanks. Just milk.
- We should go to the police. Seriously.
- That won't last. He's gay and she's an alien.
I'm not blaming you.
- Even if it was a joke that went wrong.
- Hmm. Sad ending.
- It said on the news they found a body.
- ''Rose Tyler.''
Ah! Could have been worse. Look at the ears!
- He was a nice bloke.
- # Luck be a lady... #
If we do go to the police, I wanna know
what I'm saying. I want you to explain everything.
Maybe not!
- (SCUFFLING)
- What's that, then?
- Have you got a cat?
- No.
We did have, but now we just get strays.
They come in off the estate.
I told Mickey to chuck that out.
You're all the same. Give a man a plastic hand (!)
Anyway, I don't even know your name.
Doctor what?
Agh!
I've stopped it. See?
- 'Armless (!)
- Do you think?
(ROSE) You can't just go swanning off!
(DOCTOR) Yes, I can. This is me swanning off.
(ROSE) That arm tried to kill me!
(DOCTOR) Well observed.
You can't just walk away.
- You've got to tell me what's going on.
- No, I don't.
All right. I'll go to the police.
I'll tell everyone. You said if I did that,
I'd get people killed, so, your choice.
- Tell me or I'll start talking.
- Is that supposed to sound tough?
- Sort of.
- It doesn't work.
- Who are you?
- Told you. The Doctor.
- Doctor what?
- Just the Doctor.
- The Doctor?
- Hello!
- Is that supposed to sound impressive?
- Sort of.
Come on. You can tell me. I've seen enough.
Are you the police?
No! I was just passing through.
I'm a long way from home.
What have I done wrong?
Why are those plastic things after me?
Suddenly the entire world revolves
around you (!) You just got in the way.
It tried to kill me.
It was after me, not you. I was in the shop,
you blundered in, almost ruined the whole thing.
I was tracking it down, it was tracking me down.
It only fixed on you 'cause you met me.
So you're saying
the entire world revolves around you.
- Sort of, yeah.
- You're full of it!
Sort of, yeah!
All this plastic stuff - who else knows about it?
- No one.
- What, you're on your own?
Who else is there? I mean, you lot, all you do
is eat chips, go to bed and watch telly,
while underneath you there's a war going on.
OK.
Start from the beginning.
(ROSE) If we're going with the living plastic -
I don't even believe that - how did you kill it?
The thing controlling it projects life
into the arm. I cut off the signal.
- So that's radio control?
- Thought control.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah.
- So who's controlling it, then?
- Long story.
What's it all for? I mean, shop window dummies.
What's that about?
Is someone trying to take over Britain's shops?
- (THEY LAUGH)
- No!
- Well, no.
- It's not a price war!
(THEY LAUGH)
They want to overthrow the human race
and destroy you. Do you believe me?
- No.
- But you're still listening.
Really, though, Doctor...tell me. Who are you?
Do you know like we were saying
about the Earth revolving?
It's like when you're a kid
and they tell you that the world's turning,
but everything looks like it's standing still.
I can feel it.
The turn of the Earth. The ground beneath
our feet spinning at 1,000 miles an hour,
and the entire planet is hurtling round the sun
at 67,000 miles an hour, and I can feel it.
We're falling through space, you and me,
clinging to the skin of this tiny little world,
and if we let go...
That's who I am.
Now forget me, Rose Tyler.
Go home.
(WHOOSHING)
- Hey-hey! Here's my woman. Kit off!
- Shut up.
- Coffee?
- Yeah, only if you wash the mug.
- Not rinse, wash. Can I use your computer?
- Yeah. Any excuse to get in the bedroom!
Don't read my emails!
You're not coming in. He's safe.
He's got a wife and kids.
Who told you that? He did. That's exactly
what an internet murderer would say!
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
Hello. I've come to see Clive.
We've been emailing.
Dad!
One of your nutters!
Oh, sorry. Hello.
You must be Rose. I'm Clive, obviously.
My boyfriend's waiting in the car -
just in case you're gonna kill me (!)
Good point. No murders!
- (WOMAN) Who is it?
- It's to do with the Doctor.
She's been reading the website.
Come through. I'm in the shed.
(WIFE) She?
She's read the website about the Doctor
and she's a she?
A lot of this stuff's quite sensitive. I couldn't
just send it to you. People might intercept it.
If you dig deep enough and keep a lively mind,
this Doctor crops up all over the place -
political diaries, conspiracy theories,
even ghost stories.
No first name, no last name,
just ''the Doctor'' - always ''the Doctor''.
And the title seems to be passed down
from father to son - an inheritance.
That's your Doctor there.
(ROSE) Yeah.
I tracked it down to the Washington Public
Archive last year. That photo's enhanced.
This is the original.
November 22nd 1963.
The assassination of President Kennedy.
- It must be his father.
- Going further back...
April 1912.
This is the Daniels family of Southampton
and friend.
This was taken the day
before they were due to sail on the Titanic.
For some unknown reason, they cancelled
the trip and survived. Here we are...
1883. Another Doctor.
Look - the same lineage. It's identical.
This one washed up on the coast of Sumatra
the night that Krakatoa exploded.
The Doctor is a legend woven throughout history.
When disaster comes, he's there.
He brings a storm in his wake,
and has one constant companion.
Who's that?
Death.
(RUMBLING WHEELS)
If the Doctor's back, if you've seen him, Rose,
then one thing's for certain.
We're all in danger.
Come on, then!
If he singled you out,
if the Doctor's making house calls...
then God help you!
(BIN ROARS)
(ROARING)
Agh!
(BURPS)
Who is he? Who do you think he is?
I think he's the same man.
I think he's immortal.
I think he's an alien from another world.
All right, he's a nutter! Off his head.
A complete online conspiracy freak. You win.
What are we gonna do tonight? I fancy a pizza.
- Pizza! Puh-puh-pizza!
- Or a Chinese.
Pizza!
Do you think I should try the hospital?
Suki said they had jobs going in the canteen.
Is that it, then - dishing out chips?
I could do A levels.
It's all Jimmy Stones's fault. I only left school
'cause of him and look where he ended up.
What do you think?
- Where did you meet this Doctor?
- Sorry. Did I talk about me then (?)
It started at the shop, right?
Was he something to do with that?
- No.
- Come on.
Sort of.
- What was he doing there?
- I'm not going on about it, Mickey. I'm not.
I know it sounds daft but I don't think he's safe.
He's dangerous.
You can trust me, sweetheart.
(SLIPS INT0 ALIEN V0ICE) Babe. Sugar.
Tell me what the Doctor's planning
and I can help you, Rose.
That's all I really want to do, sweetheart.
(ALIEN V0ICE) Babe. Sugar. Sweetheart.
What are you doing?
- Your champagne.
- We didn't order it.
- Where's the Doctor?
- Your champagne.
It's not ours. Mickey, what's wrong?
I need to find out how much he knows.
- Don't you want champagne?
- We didn't order it.
- Ah! Gotcha!
- Don't mind me.
Just toasting the happy couple. On the house!
Anyway...
- That's not gonna stop me.
- (MAN SCREAMS)
- (ALARM)
- Everyone out now!
(ROSE) Get out! Get out!
(BUZZING)
Open the gate! Use that tube thing.
- Sonic screwdriver.
- Use it!
Nah. Let's go in here.
You can't hide inside a wooden box!
(POUNDING METAL)
He's gonna get us!
Doctor!
He's gonna follow us!
The assembled hordes of Genghis Khan couldn't
get through that door. Believe me, they've tried.
(DOCTOR) You see, the arm was too simple,
but the head is perfect.
I can use it to trace the signal
back to the original source.
Right. Where do you want to start?
The inside is bigger than the outside.
- Yes.
- It's alien.
Yep.
Are you alien?
Yes.
- Is that all right?
- Yeah.
It's called the Tardis. T-A-R-D-I-S.
Time And Relative Dimension In Space.
- (SOBS)
- That's OK. Culture shock.
- Happens to the best of us.
- Did they kill him? Mickey?
Did they kill Mickey? Is he dead?
Oh. I didn't think of that.
He's my boyfriend. You pulled off his head.
They copied him and you didn't even think?
- And now you're just gonna let him melt?
- Melt?
- (DOCTOR YELLS) No, no, no!
- What are you doing?
Following the signal. It's fading.
- (WHOOSHING)
- No, no!
- Almost there.
- Here we go.
- (WHOOSHING)
You can't go out there. It's not safe.
I lost the signal. I got so close!
- We've moved. Does it fly?
- Disappears there and reappears here.
What about that headless thing?
It's still on the loose.
- It melted with the head. Stop wittering on.
- I'll have to tell his mother.
Mickey. I'll have to tell his mother he's dead.
You forgot him again!
- You were right. You ARE alien.
- If I did forget some kid,
it's because I'm trying to save
every stupid ape on this planet, all right?
- All right.
- Yes, it is!
- Why do you sound like you're from the north?
- Lots of planets have a north.
What's a police public call box?
It's a telephone box from the 1950s.
- It's a disguise.
- OK.
- This living plastic, what's it got against us?
- Nothing. It loves you.
You have a great planet. Lots of smoke and oil,
toxins and dioxins in the air. Perfect.
Just what the Nestene Consciousness needs.
Its food stock was destroyed.
- Its protein planets rotted, so Earth - dinner!
- Can you stop it?
- Antiplastic.
- Antiplastic?
First I've got to find it.
How can you hide something that big?
- What?
- The transmitter.
The Consciousness controls the plastic.
The transmitter boosts the signal.
- What does it look like?
- Like a transmitter. Round and massive.
Slap bang in the middle of London.
A huge metal circular structure. Like a wheel.
Close to where we're standing.
Must be completely invisible.
What?
What is it? What?
Oh.
Fantastic!
Think of it - plastic all over the world.
Everything coming alive.
The shop window dummies, phones, wires.
- The cables...
- The breast implants.
The Consciousness must be
somewhere underneath.
What about down here?
Looks good to me.
The Nestene Consciousness.
That's it inside the vat. A living plastic creature.
- Tip in your antiplastic and let's go.
- I'm not here to kill it.
I've got to give it a chance.
I seek audience with you under peaceful contract
according to Convention 15
of the Shadow Proclamation.
(ROARING)
Thank you.
If I might have permission to approach?
- (ROARING)
- Oh, God!
(ROSE) Mickey, it's me. It's OK.
It's all right.
That thing down there -
the liquid, Rose - it can talk!
You're stinking! Doctor, they kept him alive!
That was always a possibility.
That way, they maintain the copy.
- You knew that and never said?
- Can we keep the domestics outside?
- Am I addressing the Consciousness?
- (ROARING)
Thank you. You infiltrated this civilisation
by means of warp-shunt technology,
so may I respectfully suggest
that you shunt off?
(ROARING)
It's an invasion, plain and simple.
Don't talk about constitutional rights.
(ROARING)
I am talking!
This planet is just starting. These stupid people
have only just learnt to walk,
but they're capable of so much more.
- I'm asking you on their behalf. Please go.
- Doctor!
- (ROARING)
- It was just insurance. I wasn't gonna use it.
- I was not attacking you. I'm here to help.
I'm not your enemy. I swear I'm not.
(ROARING)
What do you mean? No!
Honestly, no!
- (ROARING)
- Yes, that's my ship.
(ROARING)
That's not true. I should know. I was there.
I fought in the war. It wasn't my fault.
I couldn't save your world or any of them.
- (ROARING)
- What's it doing?
The Nestene's identified the Tardis
as superior technology. It's terrified.
It's going to the final base. It's starting
the invasion. Get out, Rose. Just leg it now!
(CONSCIOUSNESS ROARS)
- Mum?
- There you are. I was just gonna phone.
You CAN get compensation. I've got
this document off the police. Don't thank me.
- Where are you, Mum?
- I'm in town.
- Just go home right now.
- You're breaking up.
I'm just gonna do a bit of late-night shopping.
See you later. Ta-ra!
Mum? Mum!
It's the activation signal. It's transmitting!
It's the end of the world.
(HUMMING)
There's no point in a spreadsheet
if you spend summer money in winter.
God! I thought they were dummies.
I nearly had a heart attack.
It's true. Everything I read -
all the stories - it's all true.
(ROARING)
- Get out, Rose! Just get out! Run!
- (ROSE) The stairs have gone!
I haven't got the key!
We're gonna die.
(SCREAMS AND BLASTS)
Agh!
(SCREAMING)
- No!
- (CONSCIOUSNESS ROARS) Time Lord!
Just leave him!
- There's nothing you can do!
- I've got no A levels.
No job. No future.
But I'll tell you what I HAVE got.
Jericho Street Junior School
Under-7s Gymnastics Team.
I've got the bronze.
(ROARING)
(DOCTOR) Rose!
Now we're in trouble!
(HUMMING STOPS)
(SCREECHING ROAR)
(WHOOSHING)
(MUM WHIMPERS)
(DIALLING)
(MOBILE RINGS)
Rose! Don't go out of the house. It's not safe.
- These things were shooting...
- (BEEP)
- Hello?
- (WAILING SIREN)
- Fat lot of good you were!
- (MICKEY WHIMPERS)
- Nestene Consciousness? Easy!
- You were useless in there.
- You'd be dead if it wasn't for me.
- Yes, I would. Thank you.
Right, then, I'll be off...unless...
I don't know... You could come with me.
This box goes anywhere in the universe
free of charge.
Don't. He's an alien. He's a thing!
He's not invited.
What do you think?
You could stay here, fill your life with work
and food and sleep, or you could go anywhere.
- Is it always this dangerous?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I can't.
I've got to go and find my mum, and someone's
got to look after this stupid lump, so...
OK.
See you around.
(WHOOSHING)
Come on, let's go. Come on.
Come on.
(WHOOSHING)
By the way, did I mention it also travels in time?
- Thanks.
- Thanks for what?
Exactly!
(DOCTOR) This is the year five billion.
And this is the day... Hold on...
Welcome to the end of the world.
(ALIEN) Who the hell are you?
I'm the Doctor. This is Rose Tyler,
my ''plus one'', OK?
Representing the Forest of Cheam,
we have trees.
The Moxx of Balhoon.
The Face of Boe.
The last human - the Lady Cassandra O'Brien.
Oh, now, don't stare! Look how thin I am!
- (JUDDERING IMPACT)
- That's not supposed to happen.