Solar flare activity has increased across
space lanes 5,5,6. All commercial flights are...
(WHOOSHING)
So, it's 200,000. It's a spaceship...
No, a space station, and, er...
- Try that gate over there.
- 200,000?
- 200,000.
- Nice.
Adam! Out you come.
- Oh, my God!
- (ROSE) Don't worry. You'll get used to it.
- Where are we?
- (ROSE) Good question. Let's see.
Judging by the architecture, I'd say we're
around the year 200,000, and if you listen...
- (HUMMING)
- Engines. We're in a space station.
Yeah, definitely a space station. It's a bit warm
in here. They could turn the heating down.
Tell you what - let's try that gate. Come on.
Here we go.
And this is...
I'll let the Doctor describe it.
The Fourth Great and Bountiful Human Empire.
There it is - Planet Earth at its height.
Covered with mega-cities, five moons,
population 96 billion.
The hub of a galactic domain stretching
across a million planets, a million species,
with mankind right in the middle.
He's your boyfriend (!)
Not anymore.
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Come on, Adam. Open your mind.
You'll like this - fantastic period of history.
The human race at its most intelligent -
art, politics, fine food, good manners...
- (MAN) Out the way!
- (WHIRRING MACHINERY)
(MAN) Is somebody there? That's great.
What do you want, love?
One at a time. What was it? Kronkburger
with cheese, kronkburger with pajatos.
Do you want a drink? Oi! Stop pushing!
Get back! I said, back!
- Fine cuisine?
- My watch must be wrong.
- No, it's fine. It's weird.
- Your history's not as good as you thought.
- It's perfect.
- Obviously not.
What about the millions of planets and species?
Where are they?
That is a good question.
- Adam, me old mate. You must be starving.
- No, I'm a bit timesick.
You need some grub.
How much is a kronkburger?
Two credits twenty, sweetheart.
Now, join the queue!
We need money. Let's use a cashpoint.
(BUZZING)
- Pocket money. Don't spend it all on sweets.
- How does it work?
Go and find out. Stop nagging me! Time travel's
like visiting Paris. Don't just read a guidebook.
Throw yourself in - eat the food, get
charged double and kiss complete strangers...
Or is that just me?
Stop asking questions. Go and do it!
- Off you go. Your first date (!)
- You're gonna get a smack, you are!
This is gonna sound daft,
but can you tell me where I am?
- Floor 139.
- Could they write it any bigger (?)
- Floor 139 of what?
- Must have been some party!
- You're on Satellite Five.
- What's that?
- How could you not know where you are?
- I'm stupid!
Wait a minute. Are you a test?
Some sort of management test kind of thing?
You've got me. You're too clever for me.
We were warned about this in basic training.
Workers have to be versed
in company promotion.
Right. Fire away. If it gets me to Floor 500,
- I'll do anything.
- What happens on Floor 500?
The walls are made of gold!
And you should know, Mr Management!
So, this is what we do.
Latest news - sandstorms
on the New Venus Archipelago, 200 dead.
The Glasgow water riots into their third day.
Space lane 77 closed by sunspot activity.
And the Face of Boe
has just announced he's pregnant.
You broadcast the news.
We ARE the news. We're the journalists.
We write it, package it and sell it.
600 channels broadcasting out of Satellite Five.
Something...is wrong.
Something fictional.
Those people.
Nothing happens in the whole empire
without it going through us.
Security check.
Go deep.
(TANN0Y) Staff are reminded that the canteen
area operates a self-cleaning table system.
Try this. It's called Zaffic.
It's like a Slush Puppy.
What flavour?
Sort of beef.
- Oh, my God!
- (SHE LAUGHS)
It's like everything's gone -
home, family - everything.
This helps. The Doctor gave it a top-up.
- Who's back home? Your mum and dad?
- Yeah.
- Phone 'em up.
- But that's 198,000 years ago.
Honestly. Try it. Go on.
- Is there a code for Planet Earth?
- Just dial!
(PHONE RINGS)
(MUM) Sorry we're not in.
Please leave a message. Thanks.
(BEEP)
Hi. It's me.
(ADAM) I've sort of gone travelling.
I met these people and we're travelling together.
I'm fine, and I'll call you later. Love you. Bye.
- That is so...
- (KLAXON BLASTS TWICE)
Oi, Mutt and Jeff! Over here.
- (C0MPUTER) Security check cleared.
- No. Something's wrong.
I can taste it.
A tiny little shift in the information.
Someone down there shouldn't be here.
Double-check. Triple-check.
Follow them.
Now, everybody behave.
We have a management inspection.
- How do you want it, by the book?
- Right from scratch, thanks.
OK, so, ladies, gentlemen,
multisex, undecided or robot,
my name is Cathica Santini Khadeni.
That's Cathica with a C, in case you want
to write to Floor 500 praising me - please do!
Feel free to ask questions.
The process of news-gathering
must open, honest and beyond bias.
- That's company policy.
- Actually, it's the law.
Thank you, Suki. OK, keep it calm.
Don't show off for the guests.
Here we go.
And...
..engage safety.
(TRILLING HUM)
(CATHICA) And three...two...
and spike.
Compressed information, streaming into her.
Reports from every city,
every country, every planet,
and they all get packaged inside her head.
She becomes part of the software.
Her brain IS the computer.
- If it goes through her, she must be a genius.
- She wouldn't remember it.
There's too much. Her head would blow up.
The brain's the processor.
Soon as it closes, she forgets.
What about all these people?
They've got tiny chips in their head, connecting
them to her. They transmit 600 channels.
Every single fact in the Empire
beams out of this place.
Now, that's what I call power.
(C0MPUTER) Analysis confirmed.
Security breach.
I knew it!
Which one? It's someone inside that room.
Which one?
(C0MPUTER) Isolating breach.
Come on. Show me. Who is it?
(R0SE) Are you 0K?
(ADAM) I can see her brain.
- Do you want to get out?
- No. This technology, it's amazing.
This technology's wrong.
Trouble?
Oh, yeah.
(ELECTRONIC BLAST)
That's it! Oh, yes! She's the liar.
Intercept and scan.
Gotcha!
(ELECTRONIC BLAST)
Suki! I wasn't even halfway. What was that for?
- Sorry. It must have been a glitch.
- Oh!
Her information's been tampered with.
There's a second biography hidden underneath.
- (ALIEN SNARLS AND GROWLS)
- Absolutely, sir.
Her data was encrypted, so there was no way
we could have found her sooner.
- (SNARLING PROTEST)
- Sorry, sir.
- (GROWLING ORDERS)
- Absolutely.
- Get her up here. Now.
- (SNARLING)
- (CHIMING)
- Promotion!
(CATHICA) Come on! This is it. Come on!
Oh, my God. Make it me.
Come on. Say my name.
Say my name!
Promotion for Suki Macrae Cantrell.
- Proceed to Floor 500.
- I don't believe it!
Floor 500!
How the hell did you manage that?
I'm above you!
I don't know. I just applied on the off chance.
And they've said yes!
It's so not fair! I've been applying
to Floor 500 for three years!
What's Floor 500?
The walls are made of gold.
(SUKI) Cathica, I'm gonna miss you!
- Floor 500! Thank you!
- I didn't do anything.
- Well, you're my lucky charm!
- All right. I'll hug anyone.
- Come on. It's not that bad.
- What, with the head thing?
- Well, she's closed it now.
- Yeah, but it...
It's everything. It freaks me out.
I just need to... If I could just...
- ..cool down. Sort of acclimatise.
- How do you mean?
Maybe I could sit on the observation deck.
Would that be all right?
Soak it in, you know.
Pretend I'm a citizen of the year 200,000.
Do you want me to come with you?
No, no. You stick with the Doctor.
You'd rather be with him.
It's gonna take a better man than me
to get between you two.
- Anyway, I'll be on the deck.
- Here you go. Take the Tardis key.
Just in case it gets a bit too much.
Yeah, like it's not weird in there (!)
(SNIGGERS)
I've got to go.
I can't keep them waiting. I'm sorry!
Say goodbye to Steve for me.
Bye!
Good riddance!
- You're talking like you'll never see her again.
- We won't.
Once you go to Floor 500, you never come back.
Have you ever been up there?
I can't. The key for the lift
only comes with promotion.
No one gets to 500 except for the chosen few.
(BEEPING)
(HOWLING WIND )
(HISSING)
Agh!
- (SUKI) Who are you?
- I'm the Editor.
What's happening?
There are bodies out there. What's going on?
While we're asking questions,
please confirm your name.
My name is Suki Macrae Cantrell.
I was born 199'89
- in the Independent Republic of Morocco.
- Liar!
Hobbies include reading and archaeology.
I'm not an expert, I just like digging.
Liar!
I want to work for Satellite Five
because my sister can't afford university
- and the pay scheme is really good.
- Liar!
Let's look at the facts, shall we?
Ah, hidden behind a genetic graft,
but that's still you.
Eva Saint Julienne -
last surviving member of the Freedom Fifteen.
- Self-declared anarchist, is that right?
- Who controls Satellite Five?
(LAUGHS)
There's the truth!
The Freedom Foundation has been
monitoring Satellite Five's transmissions.
The facts are being manipulated.
- You are lying to the people.
- Ooh, I love it. Say it again!
This whole system is corrupt.
Who do you represent?
I am merely a humble slave.
I answer to the Editor-in-chief.
- Who is he? Where is he?
- He oversees everything. Literally everything.
If you don't mind,
I'm going to have to refer this upwards.
(ALIEN SNARLS AND GROWLS)
- What is that?
- Your boss.
This has always been your boss -
since the day you were born.
(SNARLING, GROWLING)
Agh!
Give me access.
(TRILLING HUM)
- Give me...
- (ELECTRONIC BLAST)
I can learn anything!
- (TRILLING HUM)
- Let's try computers.
From the 21st century to the present day,
give me the history of the microprocessor.
Oh, my God!
We only get 20 minutes' maintenance.
- Give it a rest!
- You've never been to another floor?
I went to Floor 16 when I first arrived. That's
Medical. I got my head done. Then I came here.
Satellite Five. We work,
eat and sleep on the same floor.
- You're not Management, are you?
- At last! She's clever!
- Well, whatever it is, I don't know anything.
- Don't you ask?
- Why would I?
- You're a journalist!
- Why is all the crew human?
- What's that got to do with anything?
- There's no aliens on board. Why?
- I dunno. They're not banned or anything.
Then where are they?
I suppose Immigration's tightened up
because of the threats.
- What threats?
- I dunno.
All of them. Usual stuff. And the price of
spacewarp doubled, so that kept visitors away.
And the government on Chavic Fice collapsed,
so that lot stopped coming.
Just lots of little reasons.
Adding up to one big fact,
and you didn't even notice.
If there was a conspiracy, Satellite Five
would have seen it. We see everything.
This society's the wrong shape.
Even the technology.
- It's cutting edge!
- It's backwards. There's a door in your head!
- What do you think's going on?
- It's the attitude. The way people think.
The Great and Bountiful
Human Empire's stunted.
- How would you know?
- Trust me.
Humanity's been set back about 90 years.
When did Satellite Five start broadcasting?
91 years ago.
(ADAM) Mum, Dad, keep this message, OK?
(ADAM) Whatever you do, don't erase it.
Save it. You got that?
OK.
(TRILLING HUM)
The microprocessor became redundant
in the year 2019,
replaced by a system called SMT,
that's Single Molecule Transcription.
No, no, no! What are you doing? Come back!
Why are you doing that?
What's Floor 16? What's down there?
Sorry, um... Floor 16, that's, um...
- What do you cover?
- Medical non-emergency.
Wrong floor. I'm having technical difficulties.
- My screen keeps locking me out.
- No, that's medical.
There must be something wrong with your chip.
Yes. Yeah, of course, yeah.
- I haven't got one.
- No wonder you can't get a screen to work.
- What are you? A...student?
- Yes.
Yeah, I'm... I'm on a research project
from the University of Mars.
- The Martian boondocks. Typical!
- Yep!
- Well, you still need chipping.
- So does that mean like brain surgery?
That's an old-fashioned phrase,
but it's the same thing, yes.
Oh, OK. Never mind.
But if I get a chip...
that means I could use any computer.
Absolutely.
You'll have to pay for it.
They've stopped subsidising.
Oh, right. Sorry. Wasting your time. Thanks.
Hold on.
Can I use this?
That'll do nicely.
It all comes down to two basic types.
Type one - the head chip - inserted
into the back of the skull. 100 credits.
There's the chip. Tiny. Invisible.
No scarring.
Type two is the full info-spike.
Oh, that's the...
(MAKES WHIRRING SOUND ) thing.
That's the one. It does cost 10,000.
Oh, well, I couldn't afford it, then.
Not at all.
It turns out you've got unlimited credit.
No, but I...I couldn't have it done.
I mean...that's got to hurt.
- Hasn't it?
- Painless. Contractual guarantee.
No, my mate's waiting upstairs.
I can't have major surgery.
It takes ten minutes.
That sort of money buys a very fast picosurgeon.
No, but I...
I couldn't, though, no. It's...
Type one, you can interface
with a simple computer.
Type two, you ARE the computer.
You can transmit any piece of information
from the archive of Satellite Five,
which is just about the entire history
of the human race.
Now...
Which one's it going to be?
We're so gonna get in trouble!
(BUZZING)
- You're not allowed to touch the mainframe!
- Rose, tell her to button it.
If you vandalise the place, they'll notice!
I don't understand. We did a full security scan.
That man was there
when we found Suki Macrae Cantrell.
There were no indications about him.
And yet here he is -
clearly acting outside the parameters.
Fascinating!
- (ALIEN GROWLS COMMANDS)
- Yes, sir.
- (SNARLING, GROWLING)
- Absolutely.
At once!
Check him. Double-check him. Triple-check him.
- Quadruple.
- (SNARLING, GROWLING)
(BUZZING)
- I'm going back to work.
- Go on, then. See you.
-I can't just leave you, can I?
- Get 'em to turn the heating down.
- It's boiling. Can't they do something about it?
- It's something to do with the turbine.
- Something to do with the turbine (!)
- Well, I don't know!
Exactly. I give up on you, Cathica.
Now, Rose asked the right question.
- I thank you.
- Why is it so hot?
- Why worry about the central heating?
- Never underestimate plumbing.
Plumbing's very important.
- (C0MPUTER) Security scan complete.
- Well, who is he?
He is no one.
(LAUGHS) What does that mean?
- He is no one.
- What, you mean he has a fake ID?
He has no identification.
But everyone's registered.
We have a census for the entire Empire.
- He is no one.
- What, he doesn't exist?
- Not anywhere?
- He is no one.
What about the blonde?
- She is no one.
- Both of them?!
Well...
We all know what happens to non-entities.
They get promoted!
Bring 'em up.
Satellite Five - pipes and plumbing.
Look at the layout.
This is ridiculous.
You've got access to the computer's core.
You could look at the archive, the stock
exchange...and you're looking at pipes?
But there's something wrong.
- I suppose...
- Why, what is it?
The ventilation system. Cooling ducts,
ice filters, all working flat out,
- channelling massive amounts of heat down.
- From the top.
- (ROSE) Floor 500.
- Something is generating tons of heat.
I feel like I'm missing out on a party.
It's all going on upstairs. Fancy a trip?
- You need a key.
- Keys are just codes. I've got them right here.
Here we go. Override 215.9.
- (CATHICA) How come it gave YOU the code?
- Someone up there likes me.
(LAUGHS)
I told you it was painless.
No scarring, you see?
Perfect success.
How do I activate it?
It's a personal choice.
Some people whistle.
I know one man who triggers it
with ''Oh, Danny Boy''.
You're set on default for now.
That's a click of the fingers.
So, you mean I just...?
Click.
- Come with us.
- No way.
- Bye!
- Well, don't mention my name.
When you get in trouble, don't involve me.
That's her gone. Adam's given up.
It's just you and me.
- Yeah.
- Good.
Yep.
Oh, my God! I'm going to be sick.
(RETCHES)
Special offer.
We installed the vomit-o-matic too.
Nano-termites are in the lining of your throat.
In the event of sickness...
..they freeze the waste.
(HE GULPS)
The walls are not made of gold.
You should go back downstairs.
Tough!
I started without you. (LAUGHS)
This is fascinating! Satellite Five
contains every piece of information
within the Fourth Great and Bountiful
Human Empire -
birth certificates, shopping habits,
bank statements - but you two, you don't exist.
(GIGGLES) There's not a trace. No birth. No job.
Not the slightest kiss.
How can you walk through the world
and not leave a single footprint?
Suki!
Hello? Can you hear me?
Suki! What have you done to her?
I think she's dead.
- She's working.
- The chips in their head keep going.
- Like puppets.
- Oh! You're full of information!
It's only fair we get some information back
because, apparently, you're no one.
It's so rare not to know something.
Who are you?
It doesn't matter 'cause we're off.
Nice to meet you. Come on.
- Tell me who you are.
- That fact is keeping us alive. I won't say.
My Editor-in-chief
might convince you otherwise.
And who's that?
It may interest you to know that this is not
the Fourth Great and Bountiful Human Empire.
It's not human at all! It's merely
a place where humans happen to live.
- (ALIEN GROWLS IN PROTEST)
- Yeah.
- (SNARLING, GROWLING)
- Yep. Sorry.
It's a place where humans are allowed to live
by kind permission of my client.
(SNARLING, GROWLING)
- What is that?
- That thing's in charge of Satellite Five?
That thing, as you put it,
is in charge of the human race.
For almost 100 years, mankind's behaviour
has been controlled by its broadcast news,
edited by my superior,
your master
and humanity's guiding light, the Mighty
Jagrafess of the Holy Hadrojassic Maxarodenfoe.
I call him Max.
(SNARLING)
Create a climate of fear
and it's easy to keep the borders closed.
It's just a matter of emphasis. The right word
in the right broadcast repeated often enough
can destabilise an economy,
invent an enemy, change a vote.
So all the people on Earth are like slaves?
Well, now, there's an interesting point.
Is a slave a slave
if he doesn't know he's enslaved?
- Yes.
- Oh! I was hoping for a philosophical debate.
- Is that all I'm going to get. ''Yes''?
- Yes.
You're no fun.
Undo these. You'll find out how much fun I am.
Ooh, he's tough, isn't he?
But come on. Isn't it a great system?
You've got to admire it a little bit.
You can't hide this. Someone must have noticed.
From time to time, yes, but the computer chip
system allows me to see inside their brains.
I can see the smallest doubt, then crush it.
(EDITOR) Then they just carry on,
living the life, strutting about downstairs
and all over the Earth like they're so individual
when they're not - they're just cattle.
In that respect,
the Jagrafess hasn't changed a thing.
- What about you? You're not a Jagrabelly thing.
- Jagrafess.
- You're not a Jagrafess. You're human.
- Simply being human doesn't pay very well.
- You couldn't have done this on your own.
- No!
I represent a consortium of banks.
Money prefers a long-term investment.
Also, the Jagrafess needed a hand
to install himself.
(DOCTOR) No wonder. He's big.
- What's his lifespan?
- 3,000 years.
(DOCTOR) That's a huge metabolism generating
heat. That's why Satellite Five's so hot.
You pump it out of the creature, channel it
downstairs. Jagrafess stays cool and alive.
Satellite Five is a life-support system.
(ADAM) It's me again. Don't wipe this message.
It's just going to sound like white noise,
but save it 'cause I can translate it, OK?
Three, two, one...and spike.
But that's why you're so dangerous.
Knowledge is power, but you remain unknown.
Who are you?
(CRACKLING JOLT)
Leave her alone. I'm the Doctor,
she's Rose Tyler. We're nothing.
Tell me who you are.
- I just said.
- Who do you work for?
Who sent you? Who knows about us?
Who exactly...?
Agh!
- (TRIUMPHANT GROWL)
- Time Lord!
- What?
- (LAUGHS) Oh, yes!
The last of the Time Lords
and his travelling machine.
- With his little human girl from long ago.
- What are you talking about?
Time travel.
Agh!
Help!
Someone's been telling you lies.
Young Master Adam Mitchell?
(ADAM SCREAMS) Help! Agh!
Oh, my God, his head!
What the hell's he done?
They're reading his mind.
- He's telling them everything.
- I know everything about you.
Every piece of information in his head
is now mine.
And you have infinite knowledge, Doctor.
The Human Empire is tiny compared to
what you've seen in your T-A-R-D-I-S. Tardis.
- You'll never get that. I'll die first.
- Die all you like. I've got the key.
- You and your boyfriends!
- Today, WE are the headlines.
We can rewrite history.
We could prevent mankind from developing.
No one will stop you because you've bred
a human race which doesn't ask questions.
Stupid little slaves believing every lie.
They'll trot right into the slaughterhouse
if they're told it's made of gold.
(SNARLING)
Disengage safety.
- (BEEPING)
- What's happening?
Maximum access. Override floor 139.
And spike!
Someone's disengaged the safety.
Who's that?
(SNARLING PROTEST)
- It's Cathica!
- She's thinking. She's using what she knows!
Terminate her access!
Everything I told her about the pipes,
the filters - she's reversing it.
Look at that! It's getting hot.
I said terminate her!
Burn out her mind!
Oh, no, you don't.
You should have promoted me years back!
(SCREAMING)
She's venting the heat up here. The Jagrafess
has to stay cool - now it's on top of a volcano!
(PEOPLE SCREAM)
- (SNARLING PROTEST)
- Yes, I'm trying, sir, but...
It's impossible -
a member of staff with an idea!
(SHRIEKS)
- What do I do?
- Flick the switch!
(BELLOWING ROAR)
(WAILING ALARM)
(SHRIEKS)
Oi! Do you want to bank on a certainty?
Massive heat in a massive body -
massive bang!
See you in the headlines!
(BELLOWS)
If it's all the same to you,
I think I'll resign. Bye.
Let go of me!
(SHRIEKS)
Agh!
(BANG!)
We're gonna go. Too many questions.
You'll manage.
- No one will believe me.
- They might believe a lot of things now.
- Humans will get back to normal.
- What about your friend?
He's not my friend.
- Now, don't...
- (ADAM) I'm all right now.
Much better. And I've got the key.
Look, it's...
It all worked out for the best, didn't it?
You know, it's not actually my fault
because you were in charge...
This is my house! I'm home.
Oh, my God, I'm home! Blimey! I thought
you were going to chuck me out of an airlock.
- Is there something else you want to tell me?
- No. What do you mean?
The archive of Satellite Five. One second
of that message could have changed the world.
- That's it, then. See you.
- How do you mean, see you?
- As in goodbye.
- What about me? You can't just go.
- I have a chip type two. My head opens.
- Like this?
- Don't.
- Don't do what?
Stop it!
All right, that's enough. Stop it.
Thank you.
- Oi!
- Sorry. I couldn't resist.
- History could have changed because of you.
- I just wanted to help.
- You were helping yourself.
- I said I'm sorry, and I am.
You can't just leave me like this.
If anyone sees that head, they'll dissect you
in seconds. You'll have to lead a quiet life.
Be average. Unseen. Good luck.
But I want to come with you.
I only take the best. I've got Rose.
(ADAM) Rose!
- Oh, my God!
- (MUM) Who's that? Geoff, is that you?
- It's me, Mum. Don't come in. Wait there.
- Oh, my Lord!
You never said you were coming home!
(MUM) Hold on. I'll just take my coat off.
Rose, take me with you.
- (WHOOSHING)
- What's that noise?
Have you left the back door open?
Blimey, there's a draught!
What a surprise! Let me look at you!
Six months!
It's like I saw you yesterday.
Time goes by like that.
(WHIRRING)
Be careful what you wish for.
The day my father died. It's just an ordinary day.
Oh, God, this is it. He can't die on his own!
(ROSE) Can I try again?
- Oh, God, this is it.
- Rose, no!
- I chose another stupid ape!
- I haven't changed history.
A man is alive who wasn't alive before.
The world's different because he's alive.
Time's been damaged.
They've come to sterilise the wound.
- Get in the church!
- Agh!